A Finding Aid to the C. J. (Clarence Joseph) Bulliet Papers, circa 1888-1959, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bullclar
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1901-1952; Series 2; 2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  - Kalish, Shaindel - Kelly, Edward J., 1927-1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Kauffman, Robert
    Kaufmann, Ernst
    Keas, Philip
    Keller, Lerrey
    Kelley, Hubert N.
    Kelly, Edward J. (Mayor of Chicago)
  - Kelly, "Kid" - Kettering, Ralph T., 1929-1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Kelly, "Kid" (Mrs. Clay Kelly)
    Kempf, Tud
    Kenyon, Annetta A.
    Kessel, Lawrence
    Kettering, Ralph T.
  - Kharasch, Jerome - Kuh, Katharine, 1913-1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Kharasch, Jerome
    Kienholz, Foster
    Kienzelmann, Theobald
    King, Rose
    Kleist, Herbert
    Kline, J. E.
    Kluczewski, Felix
    Knapp, George E.
    Knight Publications, Inc.
    M. Knoedler and Co.
    Alfred A. Knopf Incorporated
    Knox, Daniel H.
    Koehler and Volckmar A.-G. and Co.
    Konapka, Harriette
    Koras, Binny
    Kramer, Arthur
    Krause, Evelyn
    C. W. Kraushaar Art Galleries
    Kroch's International Bookstore
    Kronberg, Louis
    Katharine Kuh Gallery
  - Lackner, Helen - Little Gallery, 1927-1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Lackner, Helen
    Lambert, Eleanor
    Laphin-Luidon, Laura
    Laskey, Harold H.
    Lathrop, Mrs. W. R.
    Lauter, Flora
    Lawson, Jack
    Lawton, Alice
    Layton Art Gallery
    Lazard, Alice A.
    Learned, Ann
    Lechley, E. Fred
    Lederer, Sam
    Lehman, Mahrea Cramer
    Lennon, Ralph and Margret
    Lewis, Kathryn Yager
    Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Company
    Lichtenstein, M. Salmon
    Lietz, Mattie
    Life
    Lilienfeld Galleries
    Linden, B. G.
    Lindroth, Irene
    Literary Digest
    Little Gallery
  - Lobdell, Effie L. - Lubin, Jo Moline, 1924-1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Lobdell, Effie L.
    Lockett, Ann
    Lochrane, Franz
    Longfield-Smith, Rosamunde
    Look
    Los Angeles County Fair
    Louisville Herald
    Lovitz, David
    Lowrie, E. L.
    Lubin, Jo Moline
  - John W. Luce and Company, 1917-1922 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lutz, Lilly - Lyons, Stasia, 1933-1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Lutz, Lilly
    Luxman, Eleanore
    Lyman, Betty Kessler
    Lyons, Jane
    Lyons, Stasia
  - Macmillan Company Publishers, 1923-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mahan, Donnie - Maywood Arts Club, 1917-1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Mahan, Donnie
    Mallett, Daniel Trowbridge
    Malter, L. H.
    Mandel Brothers, Club Woman's Bureau
    Mandel, Estelle
    Manley, Jeannette
    Mann, Al
    Manoir, Irving
    Mantell, Robert B.
    Mariano, Louis
    Marino, Rosemarie C.
    Markus, Nathan L.
    Mason, Roy M.
    Mathews, H. M.
    Mathis, B.
    Matisse, Pierre
    Matthias, Blanche
    Maywood Arts Club
  - McAtee, Viola - McVeigh, Blanche, 1924-1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    McAtee, Viola
    McCarthy, R. L.
    McCormick, Amy
    McCormick, Chauncey
    McCormick, Leander J., Estate of
    McCoy, Mary
    McCullough, Ethyl
    McDermott, John Francis
    McDowell, Martha
    McGill, Anna Blanche
    McGrath, W. J.
    McHugh, Genevieve
    McIntyre, O. O.
    McLinn, Charles B. (Mayor of New Albany, Ind.)
    McMartin, Mary F.
    McVeigh, Blanche
  - Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy - Metzner, C. H., 1926-1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy
    Meerdink, George A.
    Meier, Norman C.
    Mellor, N. H.
    Mengel, Robert M.
    Menters, Angus
    Merchandise Mart
    Merenkov, Olga
    Merrick, Eleanor
    Merrill, Walter McIntosh
    Metour, E. P.
    Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures
    Metropolitan Museum of Art
    Metzner, C. H.
  - Micheli, G. Armando - Mitchell, Louis J., 1923-1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Micheli, G. Armando
    Middle America Information Bureau
    Milch Galleries
    Millar, Anne George
    Miller, Clifford L.
    Miller, Elizabeth
    Miller, George "Lefty"
    Miller, Lee K.
    Miller, Morrie H.
    Millier, Arthur
    Millon, Mae L.
    Milwaukee Art Institute
    Minneapolis School of Art
    Minneapolis Tribune
    Minnesota State Fair
    Minotaure
    Minsk, Marjorie
    Minster, Carole
    Mitchell, Glenn
    Mitchell, Louis J.
  - Moessel, Julius - Myers, Margaret K., 1924-1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Moessel, Julius
    Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl
    Momentum 1950
    Montgomery, LeRoy
    Moore, Ethel M.
    Moore, Susa P.
    Morehouse, Lucille E.
    Monroe, Harry L.
    Morgan, Kenneth and Phyllis
    Morgan, Leon
    Morley, Hubert
    Morris, Edward
    Morris, Georg-Richard, III
    Mount, Cati
    Mowrer, Paul
    Municipal Art League of Chicago
    Munroe, Robert Blakewell
    Museum of Living Art, New York University
    Museum of Modern Art
    Music News Inc.
    Myers, Bernard
    Myers, Margaret K.
  - Nahigian Brothers, Inc. - Newberry, Lane K., 1927-1947 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Nahigian Brothers, Inc.
    Nash, Joseph
    Natchitoches Art Colony
    National Bureau of Standards
    National Gallery of Art
    Neild, Josephus
    Nelligan, John J.
    Nelson, Mrs. H. R.
    Neoterics
    Neumann, J. B.
    New Albany Public Library
    New Boston Store
    New Studio Gallery and School
    New York Times
    New York World's Fair
    Newark Museum
    Newberry, Lane K.
  - Nichols, Dale - Ozmun, Don and Pauline, 1913-1951 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Nichols, Dale
    Noble, Amelia
    Nolf, John J.
    Nooney, Mr. and Mrs. Dean
    North Carolina Department of Conservation and Development
    North Michigan Avenue Association
    North Shore Art League
    W. W. Norton and Company, Inc., Publishers
    Nowlan, John T.
    O'Brien, Dale
    O'Brien, Dorothy Angell
    O'Brien, P. F. O.
    Oehlschlager, Frank J.
    Official Information Bureau of Switzerland
    Offin, Charles Z.
    Oliver, Vic
    Olsen, Arthur J.
    Orloff, Gregory
    J. & M. Ottenheimer Publishers and Booksellers
    Owens, Marie
    Ozetti, Mario
    Ozmun, Don and Pauline
  - Pach, Walter - Plunkett, Eloise, 1927-1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Pach, Walter
    Paddock, George A., Jr.
    Page, Gertrude (Mrs. Grover Page, Sr.)
    Page, Grover, Jr.
    Page, Ruth
    Pageant
    Pain, Seymour
    Pallock, A. L.
    Palm Beach Post
    Palmblad, Signe
    Palmer, Peggy
    Palmer, Potter
    Pan American Council
    Panfield, Peter
    Park, Claea Cabeie
    Parker, Beau
    Parrilli, Donatello
    Pattee, Ruth S.
    Patteran Society
    Pattison, Abbott
    Paynter, Theodosia
    Pearson, Josephine C.
    Pearson, Ralph M.
    Penguin Books Inc.
    Perkins, Harley
    Perron, Morgan
    Peterson, C. S.
    Pickering, Diane
    Pink, Harry
    Piper, R. F.
    Pitman, Jack
    Plath, Karl and Meta
    Plemling, Winnefred
    Plunkett, Eloise
  - Polley, Frederick - Pulley, Kathryn, 1934-1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Polley, Frederick
    Pomerantz, J. C.
    Poore, Henry R.
    Pope, Arthur Upham
    Potts, Katherine
    Prausnitz, Helen
    Premmac, Charles
    Price, Glenn
    Prickett, Helen
    Public Works of Art Project
    Publicity Associates, Inc.
    Pulley, Kathryn
  - Quick - Robertson, Alan, 1928-1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Quick
    Rafferty, Howard
    Rahn, Muriel
    Rand McNally and Company
    Rea, James
    Reed, Alma
    Reeves, Jacqueline
    Refke, Alice
    Reibel, Bertram
    Reich, Joseph P.
    Reilly and Lee Co.
    Reincke, Charles Arno
    Reinhardt Galleries
    Remahl, F.
    Renaissance Society of the University of Chicago
    Revue Moderne
    Reynolds, Wellington Jarard
    Rhodes, Guy F.
    Rice, Nan
    Rice, Violette
    Rich, Dan
    Richardson, Esther Ruble and William
    Richmond Museum
    Rickey, George
    Richard, Jacob
    Ringling School of Art
    Rinkle, Patricia
    Risen, L.
    Rissman, Art
    Roberts, Julia R.
    Robertson, Alan
  - Robin, Sophie (Sophie Robin Nussbaum), 1941-1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rocke, Gilbert - Scheinman, Esther S., 1930-1950 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Rocke, Gilbert
    Rockford Art Association
    Rodgers, Richard and Oscar Hammerstein
    Rohe, Mrs. E. M.
    Roll, Elvira O.
    Ronnebeck, Arnold
    Rosen, Solomon
    Rosenshine, Annette
    Albert Roullier Art Galleries
    Royer, Emile L.
    Rubio, A. H.
    Russell, James J.
    Russian Trio
    Sagen, O. K.
    Salisbury Post
    Salpeter, Harry
    Samuels, Ernest
    Sanderson, Mrs. H. M.
    Sanford, E. Reynolds
    Santa Catalina Island
    Sargent, Porter
    Saubert-Wetzel, Patricia
    Saulter, Leon
    Saunders, Earl W.
    Scheinman, Esther S.
  - Schmidt, Patricia, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Schofield, Flora - Shoemaker, Lou, 1912-1952 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Schofield, Flora
    School of Design (see also Institute of Design)
    Schultz, Easter
    Schultz, Florence
    Schumann, Mrs. S. M.
    Schutze, Eva Watson
    Schutze, Martin
    Schwab, Arnold T.
    Schwartz, Earl
    Schwartz, William S.
    Scott, Frances Shimer
    Segel, David
    Shaffer, John C.
    Shaw, Frances
    Shaw, Sarah
    Shaw, William
    Shawhan, D. P.
    Sheets, Mary and Millard
    Shepard, K. Fisher
    Sherborrow, Mrs. F. J.
    Sherwood, W. J.
    Shoemaker, Lou
  - Siegel, Ann - Spero, Lili, 1913-1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Siegel, Ann
    Siems, Alice Littig
    Sills, Viola
    Simmons, William R.
    Simons, Hi
    Sinel, Joseph
    Singer, William Earl
    Sister Anna Marie
    Sister M. Margaret Eleanor
    Sister Sannisia
    Sloan, John
    Slobe, Louis
    Smith, Flora
    Smith, Horace
    Smitte, Ernest Browning
    Smolak, Louis
    Smythe, James
    Snipe, J. B.
    Snyder, Corydon Granger
    Snyder, Henry H.
    Socialist Workers Party
    Soellner, Oscar D.
    Spears, Ethel
    Spencer, Mary
    Spero, Lili
  - Stanch, Patty - Symmons, Nina F, 1911-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Stanch, Patty
    State University of Iowa
    Steele, Ivy N.
    Stein, L. M.
    Steinberg, Mr. and Mrs. N. P.
    Steinbrecher, George, Jr.
    Steiner, Martha
    Stemp, Lillian
    Stenvall, John
    Stephens, Russell Day, II
    Stevens, Clara Hatch
    W. K. Stewart Co.
    Stieglitz, Alfred
    Stillman, Jean
    Stix, Hugh S.
    Stowell, E. Z.
    Strain, Frances
    Stringfellow, Mary
    Stuart, James
    The Studio Publications, Inc.
    Sturgis and Walton Company Publishers
    Sullivan, M. Frank
    Swan, Lucile
    Sweeney, Frank J.
    Sweeney, James Johnson
    Swift, Charles H.
    Swisher, Alan
    Symington, Emily
    Symmons, Nina F.
  - Tallmadge, Thomas E. - Tyler, Mellen, 1928-1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Tallmadge, Thomas E.
    Tanner, James
    Targ, Anne
    Terwilliger, Edwin
    Thecla, Julie
    Theobald, Paul
    This Week in Chicago
    This Week Magazine
    Thomas, Alden K.
    Thomas, Howard
    Thomas, R. Monroe, Jr.
    Thompson, Ralph F.
    Thomson, John M.
    Thoreau, Nathalie
    Thorne, Anna L.
    Tilley, Earle F.
    Time
    Tobin, Jeanne L.
    Toledo Museum of Art
    Toronto Telegram
    Trane, Susan M.
    Transition
    Tretyakov Galleries, Inc.
    Turbyfill, Mark
    Turner, Alice
    Tuttle, Bruce R.
    Twin Editions
    Tyler, Mellen
  - Ufer, Walter - Watts, Mary M., 1926-1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Ufer, Walter
    Union League Club of Chicago
    United American Artists of Chicago
    United Exhibitors
    Universal-International Pictures
    University of Chicago (see also Renaissance Society of the University of Chicago)
    University of Chicago Press
    University of Illinois
    University of Michigan
    University of Wisconsin
    Universum Publishers and Distributors, Basel
    Valentine Gallery
    Vanak, Joseph
    Vanderhoogt, Gerrit
    Van Der Horst, Robert M.
    Van Der Westhuyzen, J. M.
    Van Dorn, Lou
    Vanecek, Aldrich
    Van Fornny, Oscar
    D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc.
    Van Pelt Art Galleries
    Vaucher, Max
    Vedral, Dorothy E.
    Verve
    Vickery, Charles B.
    Viking Press Inc.
    Von Lengerke and Antoine
    Robert C. Vose Galleries
    Walker, Margaret McKee
    Wallace, Doris
    R. Wallace and Sons Mfg. Co.
    Walsh, Don
    Watts, Mary M.
  - Weaver, Alice - Williams, Jessie R., 1926-1950 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Weaver, Alice
    Webb, A. C.
    Weber, Marie E.
    Weddell, Richard
    Weinberg, Helen Joy
    Weiner, Egon
    Weisenborn, Alfreda
    Weisenborn, Fritzi
    Werntz, Carl and Milicent
    E. Weyhe Books and Prints
    Whamond, Fred G.
    Wharton, S. H.
    Wheeler, Leslie MacBride
    Wheeler, Warren
    White, Emil
    White, Lena H.
    Whitney, Lois
    Whitney, Paul V. C.
    Wildenstein and co.
    Wilinowsky, Dorothea
    Willet, Robert L.
    Williams, Jessie R.
  - Williams, Wes, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Williamson, Alix B. - Ziroli Studios, 1928-1951 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Williamson, Alix B.
    Williamson, Anne
    Winn, John E.
    Winslow, Kathryn
    Winston, Margaret Grover
    Wisconsin Union
    Wolf, Peggy
    Wolfson, Flora J.
    Woman's Home Companion Service Bureau
    Wood, Betty
    Woodpecker, A.
    Woodward, Alice
    Worcester Art Museum
    Worcester, Charles H.
    Works Project Administration
    World-Herald
    Worthingon, Everett
    Wright, Edina
    Wylie, E.
    Yochim, Louise Dunn
    Howard Young Galleries, Inc.
    Zalewski, Leo L.
    Zinn, Walter
    Ziroli Studios
  - Unidentified, First Names Only, 1901-1952 (Box 2, Folder 32-34)
  - Unidentified, Initials Only, 1935-1948 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Unsigned, 1929-1951 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Illigible, 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Writings, 1929-1951; Series 3; 2 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  Writings by Bulliet consist of notes, drafts, and final manuscripts of published and unpublished articles and essays, books, fiction and poems, lectures, and reviews. Within each category, material is arranged alphabetically by title. The few writings by others are arranged chronologically by author.
  Additional writings, consisting of notes and drafts for reviews and columns, are scattered among the artist files (Series 4) and subject files (Series 5).
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  3.1: Writings by Bulliet
  3.2: Writings by Others
  - Writings by Bulliet, 3.1
    - Articles and Essays (Box 3)
      - "American Art as it Functions Today", circa 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - "Famous Female Impersonators From Achilles to Julian Eltinge", circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - "History of Journalism", 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - "How Modern Art Came to Town" (parts IV, V, and VI), published in The Chicagoan, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - "Sex Expression in Contemporary Painting", circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - "The Salon of Bouguereau", circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - "The Souls of Cities", circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Untitled, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Books (Box 3)
      - Apples and Madonnas, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 9-13)
      - The Courtezan Olympia, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 14-17)
      - The Eccentrics (unpublished) (Box 3)
        - Alexander the Great, Draft and Notes, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Bonheur, Rosa and Raymond, Draft and Notes, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Caesar and Cleopatra, Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - Carroll, Earl, Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - Fuseli, Henri, Draft and Research Materials, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - Insanity in Art, Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Jewish Artists, Draft, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        - Laurencin, Marie, Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 25)
        - Little Egypt, Notes and Research Materials, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        - Napoleon, Draft and Notes, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        - "On Reading the Language of Art," Draft and Notes, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        - Pascin, Jules, Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        - Thaw, Henry K., Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 30)
        - "Turner and the Dawn of Impressionism," Draft, Notes, and Research Materials, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 31)
        - Vigee-Le Brun, Elizabeth, Draft and Notes, circa 1888-1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        - Miscellaneous Drafts, Fragments, Notes, and Research Materials, 1925-1951 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - How Grand Opera Came to Chicago, circa 1942 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Masterpieces of Italian Art, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
      - 1934 Art Masterpieces in A Century of Progress Fine Arts Exhibition at the Art Institute of Chicago (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Robert Mantell's Romance, 1918-1920 (Box 3, Folder 38-41)
      - The Significant Moderns and Their Pictures, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
      - Venus Castina: Famous Female Impersonators, Celestial and Human, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
    - Columns (Box 4)
      - Art Digest Columns, 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - [ Chicago Daily News?] Columns, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Chicago Herald American, "The Easter Story", 1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Creative Writings (Box 4)
      - Novelettes, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Play, Synopsis of "The Realistic Painter", circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Play, Untitled, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Poems, 1920-1945 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Short Stories, 1917-1930 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
      - Fragments (unidentified), circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Lecture Texts and Notes (Box 4)
      - Claremont College Lectures and Student Lists, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Union League of Chicago, "Art Whether and Whither," Panel Discussion, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - A-Z (by title), circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Untitled, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Fragments, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      - Biographical Entries, Photo Captions, Summary Information about Paintings, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Journal Entries (trip to Pomona, Calif. June 26-June 30), circa 1939-1944 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Fragments, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Reviews (Box 4)
      - Art Reviews, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Book Reviews, 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Music Reviews, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Theater Reviews, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Writings by Others, 3.2
    - Dickie, Francis, "Mad, Bad, Sad, Happy Montparnasse!", circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      (with 7 illustrations)
    - Duncan, J. Dean, "The Chicago Evening Post", circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Grattan, C. Hartley, Untitled Article about Norman Lindsay, circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Treanor, Lucille, "A Triolet of No Consequence", circa 1888-1959 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Artist Files, 1919-1952; Series 4; 20 Linear feet Boxes 5-24
  Artist files document a wide variety of American (including many Chicagoans), European, and Asian artists from the Renaissance through the mid-twentieth century. The files consist mainly of photographs of works of art and a small number of photographs of artists. In addition, a small percentage of the files include correspondence, notes and drafts of texts or writings by Bulliet, printed material, and a few original art prints. Printed items consist of exhibition catalogs, checklists, invitations, announcements, reviews, articles, and miscellaneous clippings.
  Dates indicated are for the actual items in the folder. Many of the records in this series were on deposit at Rockford College for a number of years and are stamped "Rockford College Archives."
  - Aba-Novak, Vilmos, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Abbate, Paolo S., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Abbott, Lemuel, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Abercrombie, Gertrude, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Abrahamsen, Christian, 1938-1940 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Abramofsky, Jornel, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Abrams, Lucien, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Ackerman, Harry Gregory, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Acket, Desire, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Acuna, Luis Alberto, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Adam, Wilbur G., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Adams, Jean Crawford, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Adams, Kenneth M., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Adams, Walter Burt, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Adams, Wayman, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Adams, Winifred B., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Adomeit, George G., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Adriano, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ahlman, Gotthilf, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Aiken, Robert, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Albert, Ernest Maxwell, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Albinson, Dewey, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Albright, Adam Emory, 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Albright, Ivan Le Lorraine and Zsissly (Malvin Marr Albright), 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Albright, Malvin Marr (Zsissly), circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Albrizio, Conrad, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Albro, Maxine, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Aldis, Mary, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Aldrich, George, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Alexander, Anita Venier, 1931-1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Alkers, H., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Alkin, S., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Allen, Louise, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Allgard, B., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Allworthy, Joseph, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Alma-Tadema, Laurence, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Altdorfer, Albrecht, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Aman-Jean, Edmond, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Amarsolo, F., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Amateis, E., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Amberger, Christoph, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Ambrose, Lester J., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Ament, Don, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Amlauer, Herman, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Anderson, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Anderson, Anne P., 1929 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Anderson, Karl, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Anderson, Ruth A., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Anderson, Tennessee Mitchell, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Ainsfield, Boris, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Andre, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Andre, Albert, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Andrea, Zoan, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Andreatti, Libero, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Andrene, Camille, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Andreu, Mariano, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Angarola, Anthony, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Angel, Rifka, 1929-1944 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Anglada y Camarasa, Hermengildo, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Anglico de Fiesole, Fra, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Archer, Edmund, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Archipenko, Alexander, 1921-1951 (Box 5, Folder 62-64)
  - Arimany, Jaime and Valero Lecha, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Arkhipov, Abram, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Arko Studio, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Armin, Emil, 1930-1944 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Arms, John Taylor, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Aronson, Charlotte, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Aronson, Naoum, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Arp, Hans, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Arquin, Florence, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Asbjornsen, Sigurd, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Asplund, E. G., circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Asselin, Maurice, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Ast, Balthasar Van Der, circa 1888-1959 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Atget, Eugene, 1925; (1925 photographs printed by Berenice Abbott) (Box 5, Folder 78)